[
    {
        "question": "2. An administrator issues the commands: Router(config)# interface g0/1 Router(config-if)# ip address dhcp. What is the administrator trying to achieve?",
        "choices": ["configuring the router to act as a DHCPv4 server", "configuring the router to obtain IP parameters from a DHCPv4 server", "configuring the router to act as a relay agent", "configuring the router to resolve IP address conflicts"],
        "answer": "configuring the router to obtain IP parameters from a DHCPv4 server"
    },
    {
        "question": "3. When a client is requesting an initial address lease from a DHCP server, why is the DHCPREQUEST message sent as a broadcast?",
        "choices": ["The client does not yet know the IP address of the DHCP server that sent the offer.", "The DHCP server may be on a different subnet, so the request must be sent as a broadcast.", "The client does not have a MAC address assigned yet, so it cannot send a unicast message at Layer 2.", "The client may have received offers from multiple servers, and the broadcast serves to implicitly decline those other offers."],
        "answer": "The client may have received offers from multiple servers, and the broadcast serves to implicitly decline those other offers."
    },
    {
        "question": "4. Which DHCP IPv4 message contains the following information? Destination address: 255.255.255.255, Client IPv4 address: 0.0.0.0, Default gateway address: 0.0.0.0, Subnet mask: 0.0.0.0",
        "choices": ["DHCPACK", "DHCPDISCOVER", "DHCPOFFER", "DHCPREQUEST"],
        "answer": "DHCPDISCOVER"
    },
    {
        "question": "7. Refer to the exhibit. PC1 is configured to obtain a dynamic IP address from the DHCP server. PC1 has been shut down for two weeks. When PC1 boots and tries to request an available IP address, which destination IP address will PC1 place in the IP header?",
        "choices": ["192.168.1.1", "192.168.1.255", "255.255.255.255", "192.168.1.8"],
        "answer": "255.255.255.255"
    },
    {
        "question": "8. Which message does an IPv4 host use to reply when it receives a DHCPOFFER message from a DHCP server?",
        "choices": ["DHCPOFFER", "DHCPDISCOVER", "DHCPREQUEST", "DHCPACK"],
        "answer": "DHCPREQUEST"
    },
    {
        "question": "9. Which command, when issued in the interface configuration mode of a router, enables the interface to acquire an IPv4 address automatically from an ISP, when that link to the ISP is enabled?",
        "choices": ["service dhcp", "ip address dhcp", "ip helper-address", "ip dhcp pool"],
        "answer": "ip address dhcp"
    },
    {
        "question": "10. Which kind of message is sent by a DHCP client when its IP address lease has expired?",
        "choices": ["a DHCPDISCOVER unicast message", "a DHCPREQUEST broadcast message", "a DHCPREQUEST unicast message", "a DHCPDISCOVER broadcast message"],
        "answer": "a DHCPREQUEST unicast message"
    },
    {
        "question": "11. A host PC is attempting to lease an address through DHCP. What message is sent by the server to let the client know it is able to use the provided IP information?",
        "choices": ["DHCPDISCOVER", "DHCPOFFER", "DHCPREQUEST", "DHCPACK", "DHCPNACK"],
        "answer": "DHCPACK"
    },
    {
        "question": "12. What is one indication that a Windows computer did not receive an IPv4 address from a DHCP server?",
        "choices": ["The computer cannot ping 127.0.0.1.", "The computer receives an IP address that starts with 169.254.", "Windows displays a DHCP timeout message.", "The computer cannot ping other devices on the same network with IP addresses in the 169.254.0.0/16 range."],
        "answer": "The computer receives an IP address that starts with 169.254."
    },
    {
        "question": "13. Which DHCPv4 message will a client send to accept an IPv4 address that is offered by a DHCP server?",
        "choices": ["broadcast DHCPACK", "broadcast DHCPREQUEST", "unicast DHCPACK", "unicast DHCPREQUEST"],
        "answer": "broadcast DHCPREQUEST"
    },
    {
        "question": "14. A small coffee shop is offering free Wi-Fi to customers. The network includes a wireless router and a DSL modem that is connected to the local phone company. What method is typically used to configure the connection to the phone company?",
        "choices": ["Set the WAN connection in the wireless router as a DHCP client.", "Set the connection between the wireless router and the DSL modem as a private IP network.", "Set the DSL modem as a DHCP client to get a public IP address from the wireless router.", "Set the DSL modem as a DHCP client to the phone company and a DHCP server for the internal connection."],
        "answer": "Set the WAN connection in the wireless router as a DHCP client."
    },
    {
        "question": "16. A client device on an Ethernet segment needs an IP address in order to communicate on the network. A DHCP server with IP address 192.168.1.1 has been configured and enabled on the network. How will a client device obtain a usable IP address for this network?",
        "choices": ["Send a DHCPACK packet to the default gateway address.", "Use a statically configured IP address from the pool of IP addresses that is offered by the DHCP server.", "Send a DHCPDISCOVER message to physical address FF-FF-FF-FF-FF-FF.", "Send a DHCPREQUEST packet to IP address 255.255.255.255."],
        "answer": "Send a DHCPDISCOVER message to physical address FF-FF-FF-FF-FF-FF."
    },
    {
        "question": "17. What is an advantage of configuring a Cisco router as a relay agent?",
        "choices": ["It can provide relay services for multiple UDP services.", "It reduces the response time from a DHCP server.", "It can forward both broadcast and multicast messages on behalf of clients.", "It will allow DHCPDISCOVER messages to pass without alteration."],
        "answer": "It can provide relay services for multiple UDP services."
    },
    {
        "question": "18. Which statement is true about DHCP operation?",
        "choices": ["When a device that is configured to use DHCP boots, the client broadcasts a DHCPDISCOVER message to identify any available DHCP servers on the network.", "A client must wait for lease expiration before it sends another DHCPREQUEST message.", "If the client receives several DHCPOFFER messages from different servers, it sends a unicast DHCPREQUEST message to the server from which it chooses to obtain the IP information.", "The DHCPDISCOVER message contains the IP address and subnet mask to be assigned, the IP address of the DNS server, and the IP address of the default gateway."],
        "answer": "When a device that is configured to use DHCP boots, the client broadcasts a DHCPDISCOVER message to identify any available DHCP servers on the network."
    },
    {
        "question": "20. A network administrator configures a router to send RA messages with M flag as 0 and O flag as 1. Which statement describes the effect of this configuration when a PC tries to configure its IPv6 address?",
        "choices": ["It should contact a DHCPv6 server for the prefix, the prefix-length information, and an interface ID that is both random and unique.", "It should use the information that is contained in the RA message and contact a DHCPv6 server for additional information.", "It should use the information that is contained in the RA message exclusively.", "It should contact a DHCPv6 server for all the information that it needs."],
        "answer": "It should use the information that is contained in the RA message and contact a DHCPv6 server for additional information."
    },
    {
        "question": "21. Refer to the exhibit. What should be done to allow PC-A to receive an IPv6 address from the DHCPv6 server?",
        "choices": ["Add the ipv6 dhcp relay command to interface Fa0/0.", "Change the ipv6 nd managed-config-flag command to ipv6 nd other-config-flag.", "Configure the ipv6 nd managed-config-flag command on interface Fa0/1.", "Add the IPv6 address 2001:DB8:1234:5678::10/64 to the interface configuration of the DHCPv6 server."],
        "answer": "Add the ipv6 dhcp relay command to interface Fa0/0."
    },
    {
        "question": "22. Refer to the exhibit. A network administrator is implementing the stateless DHCPv6 operation for the company. Clients are configuring IPv6 addresses as expected. However, the clients are not getting the DNS server address and the domain name information configured in the DHCP pool. What could be the cause of the problem?",
        "choices": ["The DNS server address is not on the same network as the clients are on.", "The router is configured for SLAAC operation.", "The GigabitEthernet interface is not activated.", "The clients cannot communicate with the DHCPv6 server, evidenced by the number of active clients being 0."],
        "answer": "The router is configured for SLAAC operation."
    },
    {
        "question": "24. A company uses the SLAAC method to configure IPv6 addresses for the employee workstations. Which address will a client use as its default gateway?",
        "choices": ["the global unicast address of the router interface that is attached to the network", "the unique local address of the router interface that is attached to the network", "the all-routers multicast address", "the link-local address of the router interface that is attached to the network"],
        "answer": "the link-local address of the router interface that is attached to the network"
    },
    {
        "question": "25. Refer to the exhibit. A network administrator is configuring a router for DHCPv6 operation. Which conclusion can be drawn based on the commands?",
        "choices": ["The router is configured for stateful DHCPv6 operation, but the DHCP pool configuration is incomplete.", "The DHCPv6 server name is ACAD_CLASS.", "Clients would configure the interface IDs above 0010.", "The router is configured for stateless DHCPv6 operation."],
        "answer": "The router is configured for stateless DHCPv6 operation."
    },
    {
        "question": "26. A network administrator is analyzing the features that are supported by different first-hop router redundancy protocols. Which statement describes a feature that is associated with HSRP?",
        "choices": ["HSRP uses active and standby routers.", "HSRP is nonproprietary.", "It allows load balancing between a group of redundant routers.", "It uses ICMP messages in order to assign the default gateway to hosts."],
        "answer": "HSRP uses active and standby routers."
    },
    {
        "question": "27. Refer to the exhibit. What protocol can be configured on gateway routers R1 and R2 that will allow traffic from the internal LAN to be load balanced across the two gateways to the Internet?",
        "choices": ["GLBP", "PVST+", "PVST", "STP"],
        "answer": "GLBP"
    },
    {
        "question": "28. Refer to the exhibit. A network engineer is troubleshooting host connectivity on a LAN that uses a first hop redundancy protocol. Which IPv4 gateway address should be configured on the host?",
        "choices": ["192.168.2.0", "192.168.2.1", "192.168.2.2", "192.168.2.100"],
        "answer": "192.168.2.100"
    },
    {
        "question": "29. Refer to the exhibit. Which destination MAC address is used when frames are sent from the workstation to the default gateway?",
        "choices": ["MAC address of the virtual router", "MAC address of the standby router", "MAC addresses of both the forwarding and standby routers", "MAC address of the forwarding router"],
        "answer": "MAC address of the virtual router"
    },
    {
        "question": "31. Which FHRP implementation is a Cisco-proprietary protocol that suppports IPv4 load sharing?",
        "choices": ["IRDP", "GLBP", "VRRPv3", "GLBP for IPv6"],
        "answer": "GLBP"
    },
    {
        "question": "32. The address pool of a DHCP server is configured with 10.92.71.0/25. The network administrator reserves 8 IP addresses for servers. How many IP addresses are left in the pool to be assigned to other hosts?",
        "choices": ["122", "118", "119", "108", "116"],
        "answer": "118"
    },
    {
        "question": "34. After a host has generated an IPv6 address by using the DHCPv6 or SLAAC process, how does the host verify that the address is unique and therefore usable?",
        "choices": ["The host sends an ICMPv6 echo request message to the DHCPv6 or SLAAC-learned address and if no reply is returned, the address is considered unique.", "The host sends an ICMPv6 neighbor solicitation message to the DHCP or SLAAC-learned address and if no neighbor advertisement is returned, the address is considered unique.", "The host checks the local neighbor cache for the learned address and if the address is not cached, it it considered unique.", "The host sends an ARP broadcast to the local link and if no hosts send a reply, the address is considered unique."],
        "answer": "The host sends an ICMPv6 neighbor solicitation message to the DHCP or SLAAC-learned address and if no neighbor advertisement is returned, the address is considered unique."
    },
    {
        "question": "35. Which statement describes HSRP?",
        "choices": ["It is used within a group of routers for selecting an active device and a standby device to provide gateway services to a LAN.", "It uses ICMP to allow IPv4 hosts to locate routers that provide IPv4 connectivity to remote IP networks.", "If the virtual router master fails, one router is elected as the virtual router master with the other routers acting as backups.", "It is an open standard protocol."],
        "answer": "It is used within a group of routers for selecting an active device and a standby device to provide gateway services to a LAN."
    },
    {
        "question": "36. What is the keyword that is displayed on www.netacad.com?",
        "choices": ["DHCP", "switch", "Router", "networking", "Cisco", "IPv6"],
        "answer": "Router"
    },
    {
        "question": "43. The address pool of a DHCP server is configured with 192.168.234.0/27. The network administrator reserves 22 IP addresses for IP phones. How many IP addresses are left in the pool to be assigned to other hosts?",
        "choices": ["10", "0", "8", "21", "18"],
        "answer": "8"
    },
    {
        "question": "44. A company uses DHCP servers to dynamically assign IPv4 addresses to employee workstations. The address lease duration is set as 5 days. An employee returns to the office after an absence of one week. When the employee boots the workstation, it sends a message to obtain an IP address. Which Layer 2 and Layer 3 destination addresses will the message contain?",
        "choices": ["both MAC and IPv4 addresses of the DHCP server", "FF-FF-FF-FF-FF-FF and IPv4 address of the DHCP server", "FF-FF-FF-FF-FF-FF and 255.255.255.255", "MAC address of the DHCP server and 255.255.255.255"],
        "answer": "FF-FF-FF-FF-FF-FF and 255.255.255.255"
    },
    {
        "question": "45. Which command will allow a network administrator to check the IP address that is assigned to a particular MAC address?",
        "choices": ["Router# show running-config I section_dhcp", "Router# show ip dhcp server statistics", "Router# show ip dhcp binding", "Router# show ip dhcp pool"],
        "answer": "Router# show ip dhcp binding"
    },
    {
        "question": "46. What is the reason that an ISP commonly assigns a DHCP address to a wireless router in a SOHO environment?",
        "choices": ["better network performance", "better connectivity", "easy IP address management", "easy configuration on ISP firewall"],
        "answer": "easy IP address management"
    },
    {
        "question": "47. What information can be verified through the show ip dhcp binding command?",
        "choices": ["the IPv4 addresses that are assigned to hosts by the DHCP server", "that DHCPv4 discover messages are still being received by the DHCP server", "the IPv4 addresses that have been excluded from the DHCPv4 pool", "the number of IP addresses remaining in the DHCP pool"],
        "answer": "the IPv4 addresses that are assigned to hosts by the DHCP server"
    },
    {
        "question": "48. What is the result of a network technician issuing the command ip dhcp excluded-address 10.0.15.1 10.0.15.15 on a Cisco router?",
        "choices": ["The Cisco router will exclude only the 10.0.15.1 and 10.0.15.15 IP addresses from being leased to DHCP clients.", "The Cisco router will exclude 15 IP addresses from being leased to DHCP clients.", "The Cisco router will automatically create a DHCP pool using a /28 mask.", "The Cisco router will allow only the specified IP addresses to be leased to clients."],
        "answer": "The Cisco router will exclude 15 IP addresses from being leased to DHCP clients."
    },
    {
        "question": "50. Refer to the exhibit. Based on the output that is shown, what kind of IPv6 addressing is being configured?",
        "choices": ["stateless DHCPv6", "SLAAC", "static link-local", "stateful DHCPv6"],
        "answer": "stateless DHCPv6"
    },
    {
        "question": "51. Which FHRP implementation is a Cisco-proprietary protocol that suppports IPv6 load balancing?",
        "choices": ["GLBP", "GLBP for IPv6", "VRRPv3", "VRRPv2"],
        "answer": "GLBP for IPv6"
    },
    {
        "question": "52. Which set of commands will configure a router as a DHCP server that will assign IPv4 addresses to the 192.168.100.0/23 LAN while reserving the first 10 and the last addresses for static assignment?",
        "choices": [
            "ip dhcp excluded-address 192.168.100.1 192.168.100.9\nip dhcp excluded-address 192.168.101.254\nip dhcp pool LAN-POOL-100\nip network 192.168.100.0 255.255.254.0\nip default-gateway 192.168.100.1",
            "dhcp pool LAN-POOL-100\nip dhcp excluded-address 192.168.100.1 192.168.100.9\nip dhcp excluded-address 192.168.100.254\nnetwork 192.168.100.0 255.255.254.0\ndefault-router 192.168.101.1",
            "ip dhcp excluded-address 192.168.100.1 192.168.100.10\nip dhcp excluded-address 192.168.100.254\nip dhcp pool LAN-POOL-100\nnetwork 192.168.100.0 255.255.255.0\nip default-gateway 192.168.100.1",
            "ip dhcp excluded-address 192.168.100.1 192.168.100.10\nip dhcp excluded-address 192.168.101.254\nip dhcp pool LAN-POOL-100\nnetwork 192.168.100.0 255.255.254.0\ndefault-router 192.168.100.1"
        ],
        "answer": "ip dhcp excluded-address 192.168.100.1 192.168.100.10\nip dhcp excluded-address 192.168.101.254\nip dhcp pool LAN-POOL-100\nnetwork 192.168.100.0 255.255.254.0\ndefault-router 192.168.100.1"
    },
    {
        "question": "53. What is a result when the DHCP servers are not operational in a network?",
        "choices": ["Workstations are assigned with the IP address 127.0.0.1.", "Workstations are assigned with IP addresses in the 10.0.0.0/8 network.", "Workstations are assigned with IP addresses in the 169.254.0.0/16 network.", "Workstations are assigned with the IP address 0.0.0.0."],
        "answer": "Workstations are assigned with IP addresses in the 169.254.0.0/16 network."
    },
    {
        "question": "54. A company uses the method SLAAC to configure IPv6 addresses for the workstations of the employees. A network administrator configured the IPv6 address on the LAN interface of the router. The interface status is UP. However, the workstations on the LAN segment did not obtain the correct prefix and prefix length. What else should be configured on the router that is attached to the LAN segment for the workstations to obtain the information?",
        "choices": ["R1(config)# ipv6 dhcp pool", "R1(config-if)# ipv6 enable", "R1(config)# ipv6 unicast-routing", "R1(config-if)# ipv6 nd other-config-flag"],
        "answer": "R1(config)# ipv6 unicast-routing"
    },
    {
        "question": "55. Which FHRP implementation is a nonproprietary protocol which relies on ICMP to provide IPv4 redundancy?",
        "choices": ["VRRPv3", "GLBP for IPv6", "IRDP", "GLBP"],
        "answer": "IRDP"
    },
    {
        "question": "56. Refer to the exhibit. PC-A is unable to receive an IPv6 address from the stateful DHCPv6 server. What is the problem?",
        "choices": ["The ipv6 dhcp relay command should be applied to interface Gig0/0.", "The ipv6 nd managed-config-flag should be applied to interface Gig0/1.", "The ipv6 dhcp relay command should use the link-local address of the DHCP server.", "The ipv6 nd managed-config-flag command should be ipv6 nd other-config-flag."],
        "answer": "The ipv6 dhcp relay command should be applied to interface Gig0/0."
    },
    {
        "question": "57. Refer to the exhibit. A network administrator is configuring a router as a DHCPv6 server. The administrator issues a show ipv6 dhcp pool command to verify the configuration. Which statement explains the reason that the number of active clients is 0?",
        "choices": ["The default gateway address is not provided in the pool.", "No clients have communicated with the DHCPv6 server yet.", "The IPv6 DHCP pool configuration has no IPv6 address range specified.", "The state is not maintained by the DHCPv6 server under stateless DHCPv6 operation."],
        "answer": "The state is not maintained by the DHCPv6 server under stateless DHCPv6 operation."
    },
    {
        "question": "58. Which FHRP implementation is Cisco-proprietary and permits only one router in a group to forward IPv6 packets?",
        "choices": ["VRRPv3", "HSRP", "HSRP for IPv6", "VRRPv2"],
        "answer": "HSRP for IPv6"
    },
    {
        "question": "59. Which FHRP implementation is a nonproprietary IPv4-only election protocol which has one master router per group?",
        "choices": ["HSRP for IPv6", "GLBP", "VRRPv2", "VRRPv3"],
        "answer": "VRRPv2"
    },
    {
        "question": "60. The address pool of a DHCP server is configured with 172.18.93.0/25. The network administrator reserves 10 IP addresses for web servers. How many IP addresses are left in the pool to be assigned to other hosts?",
        "choices": ["106", "117", "114", "120", "116"],
        "answer": "116"
    },
    {
        "question": "61. The address pool of a DHCP server is configured with 10.3.2.0/24. The network administrator reserves 3 IP addresses for printers. How many IP addresses are left in the pool to be assigned to other hosts?",
        "choices": ["252", "241", "255", "249", "251"],
        "answer": "251"
    },
    {
        "question": "62. The address pool of a DHCP server is configured with 172.23.143.0/26. The network administrator reserves 14 IP addresses for file servers. How many IP addresses are left in the pool to be assigned to other hosts?",
        "choices": ["58", "48", "50", "61", "40"],
        "answer": "48"
    },
    {
        "question": "63. The address pool of a DHCP server is configured with 10.7.30.0/24. The network administrator reserves 5 IP addresses for printers. How many IP addresses are left in the pool to be assigned to other hosts?",
        "choices": ["253", "239", "249", "250", "247"],
        "answer": "249"
    },
    {
        "question": "64. Which FHRP implementation is a nonproprietary IPv4-only election protocol with limited scalability?",
        "choices": ["VRRPv2", "GLBP", "GLBP for IPv6", "IRDP"],
        "answer": "VRRPv2"
    },
    {
        "question": "65. The address pool of a DHCP server is configured with 192.168.184.0/26. The network administrator reserves 18 IP addresses for access points. How many IP addresses are left in the pool to be assigned to other hosts?",
        "choices": ["57", "44", "54", "36", "46"],
        "answer": "44"
    },
    {
        "question": "66. The address pool of a DHCP server is configured with 10.19.44.0/24. The network administrator reserves 3 IP addresses for servers. How many IP addresses are left in the pool to be assigned to other hosts?",
        "choices": ["255", "252", "241", "251", "249"],
        "answer": "251"
    },
    {
        "question": "67. The address pool of a DHCP server is configured with 10.19.44.0/24. The network administrator reserves 6 IP addresses for servers. How many IP addresses are left in the pool to be assigned to other hosts?",
        "choices": ["246", "252", "249", "248", "238"],
        "answer": "248"
    },
    {
        "question": "68. The address pool of a DHCP server is configured with 172.21.121.0/25. The network administrator reserves 12 IP addresses for web servers. How many IP addresses are left in the pool to be assigned to other hosts?",
        "choices": ["115", "114", "118", "104", "112"],
        "answer": "114"
    },
    {
        "question": "69. Which kind of message is sent by a DHCP client when its IP address lease is about to expire?",
        "choices": ["a DHCPREQUEST broadcast message", "a DHCPDISCOVER unicast message", "a DHCPDISCOVER broadcast message", "a DHCPREQUEST unicast message"],
        "answer": "a DHCPREQUEST unicast message"
    }
]